Hi, I'm Chris.
I'm a Diversity Program
Manager here at Google.
Influencing is a huge component
when it comes to
program management.
You might have an incredible idea
about where you want a
program or a project to go,
and so once you have
come up with all
these creative ideas,
and you want to convince
someone to sign off on it,
you have to think about
what's in it for them.
What's the impact
that this project or
program is going to
have on the business,
on the consumer, what have you,
and so once you are
able to distill
what that impact is going to be,
you can really think
about how you're going to
frame the ask to that
executive stakeholder.
Influencing, everyone has
the ability to do it.
You've done it since
you were a kid,
whether it be trying
to go out and
play with your friends or get
your favorite meal from
the favorite restaurant
that you have.
You've always tried to influence
someone to give
you what you want,
but you have to think about
what the value is for them.
So different, when you're a kid,
the value is only really for you.
When I first came into my role
as a diversity program manager,
there were a set of programs
that had been around
for a number of years,
and I came in,
I had a fresh set of eyes,
and I recognized that
there's a lot of
redundancy with the
programs that we had.
What I did is came in and I
had to influence people that
had been running those programs,
that their programs were
all very similar in that
if we all work together,
we'd be able to build
just one program that
solves all these needs.
Now that took some time, right?
I had to show examples
of why I think
this singular
program could impact
the target population in the
same way I had to show how
each person would have a role
in this new found program, right?
I couldn't just say like all
of your programs need to stop.
It was more so all your
programs need to mature
into this new identity,
so it took some time.
It really also took a lot of
relationship massaging
and maturing
because I was a new guy,
so I had to come in
and prove myself.
The impact was shown
pretty soon after because
it was thought through
well in advance.
My advice is: keep it simple.
So, you have all of
the background information
about why this is important,
all the steps it will
take you to get there,
but the person who you're
trying to influence just needs to
know when you're going to get
there and basic information
on how you're going to get there.
And so, don't try to bring
them into the weeds with you.
Keep them at a point
that makes sense for the
audience that you're in.
So if you're talking
to a researcher,
they might want to
know the data points.
So, talking to the marketing team,
they want to probably know
the more splashy
high-level elements
and the target demographics.
So keep in mind your
audience, but keep it simple.
Influencing doesn't
need to be a chore.
Once you've done the work,
you should be excited to
talk to someone about it,
and so, if you don't feel
excited about the work
that you're doing,
I would take a step
back and think
about what it is that
you are building,
what it is that you're
putting together,
and if it doesn't excite you,
it's not going to
excite somebody else.